Guide to the Robin McDouall Correspondence
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Robin McDouall correspondence
1933-1982
GEN MSS 875
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.21
(1 box)
The collection consists of letters received by McDouall from his friends Harold Acton, Patrick Leigh Fermor, Evie Hone, John Sparrow, Cecil Woodham Smith, and others. They are personal in nature and include many invitations and thank-you notes. Also present is one photograph of two unidentified men.
McDouall, Robin, 1908-
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Maggs Brothers, Ltd. on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1998.
Robin McDouall (b. 1908)
Robin McDouall, British author of books on cooking and dining.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of letters received by McDouall from his friends Harold Acton, Patrick Leigh Fermor, Evie Hone, John Sparrow, Cecil Woodham Smith, and others. They are personal in nature and include many invitations and thank-you notes. Also present is one photograph of two unidentified men.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Authors, English -- 20th Century -- Archives; English literature -- 20th Century; Dinners and dining -- England; Photographs; Authors, English -- 20th Century; Acton, Harold, 1904-1994; Fermor, Patrick Leigh, 1915-2011; Hone, Evie, 1894-1955; McDouall, Robin, 1908-; Sparrow, John, 1906-1992; Woodham Smith, Cecil, 1896-1977
- Letters, 1933-1982
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Acton, Harold, 1958, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clonmore, Billy
  - Cooper, Billy, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fermor, Patrick Leigh, 1953-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fielding, Daphne Vivian, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - [H?.], Roger, 1933-1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Home of the Hirsel, Alec Douglas-Home, Baron, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Home, William Douglas, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hone, Evie, 1949-1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Lehmann, Rosamond, 1954 Feb 17 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Leppard, Raymond, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Macaulay, Rose, 1958, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - March, H. W., 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Marshall, Arthur, 1979 Feb 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Morris, Jan [James], 1971-1982, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Orwell, Sonia, 1967 Jul 5 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Phillip, J., undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Plomer, William, 1951 Nov 5 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Powell, Anthony, 1978 Dec 1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Pryce-Jones, Alan, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Sparrow, John, 1958-1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Spurling, Hilary, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1978 Jan 8 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Wicklow, William Cecil James Philip John Paul Howard, Earl of, 1946 Jun 5 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Woodham Smith, Cecil, 1954-1968 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Unidentified, 1959-1969, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Photograph of two unidentified men, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)